Guide to the Don Edward Fehrenbacher Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Don Edward Fehrenbacher papers
1928-1997
SC0211
Fehrenbacher, Don Edward, 1920-1997.
11.5 Linear feet (25 boxes)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Prof. Don E. Fehrenbacher, 1979-1997, and of Mrs. Don E. Fehrenbacher, 1999.
Information about Access
None.
Biography
Don Edward Fehrenbacher, noted Lincoln scholar and winner of the Nobel Prize in history in 1979 for his book The Dred Scott Case, was the William Robertson Coe Professor of History and American Studies at Stanford University. He earned his B.A. at Cornell University in 1946 and his graduate degrees at the University of Chicago (M.A. 1948 and Ph.D. 1951). He taught at Coe College in Iowa, 1949 to 1953, before coming to Stanford in 1953.
His awards included a Guggenheim fellowship in 1959-60, a National Endowment for the Humanities fellowship, 1975-76, and the Lincoln Prize for Civil War studies in 1997. He was the Harmsworth Professor of American History at Oxford University, 1967-68, and the Harrison Professor of History at the College of William and Mary, 1973-74.
His other books included Prelude to Greatness: Lincoln in the 1850s, A Basic History of California, and The Era of Expansion 1800-1848. With his Stanford colleague David Potter, he coedited The South and the Concurrent Majority.
Fehrenbacher was appointed Professor Emeritus in 1984; he continued to lecture and publish during his retirement and was a consultant on Ken Burns' epic film The Civil War, which aired in 1990. He died in December 1997.
Scope and Content
These papers document Fehrenbacher's career as historian, writer, and professor at Stanford University. Included are his incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1945-1997; syllabi, lectures, and examinations from his classes; manuscripts, drafts, and some research files from his books The Dred Scott Case and The Minor Affair; reference files, notes, lectures, and published articles (largely from his research on Abraham Lincoln), ca. 1948-1988; and reviews of his published works.
The correspondence, arranged chronologically, is with other historians, publishers, professional associations, Stanford colleagues, and his students, with some family letters included. Correspondents include McDonald Forrest, Bernard Weisberger, William T. Hutchinson, Lionel E. Fredman, Norman Graebner, Michael Burlingame, Carl N. Degler, David M. Potter, George H. Knoles, Richard W. Lyman, and Earl Pomeroy.
Access Terms
Burlingame, Michael,, 1941-; Degler, Carl N.; Fredman, Lionel E.; Graebner, Norman A.; Hutchinson, William T., (William Thomas), 1895-1976.; Knoles, George Harmon.; Lyman, Richard W., 1923-2012.; McDonald, Forrest.; Pomeroy, Earl S., (Earl Spencer), 1915-2005.; Potter, David Morris; Stanford University. Department of History. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Weisberger, Bernard A.,, 1922-; Manuscripts (for publication).; Slavery--Law and legislation--United States.; United States--History--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- CORRESPONDENCE, SERIES 1
  - 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1952 January - March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1952 April - June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1952 July - September (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1952 October - December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1953 January - February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1953 March (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1953 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1953 May - June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1953 July - September (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1953 October - December (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1954 January - June (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1954 July - December (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1955 January - June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1955 July - December (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1956 January - June (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1956 July - December (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1957 January - March (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1957 April - June (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1957 July - September (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1957 October - December (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1958 January - March (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1958 April - June (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1958 July - September (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1958 October - December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1959 January - March (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1959 April - June (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1959 July - September (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1959 October - December (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1960 January - March (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1960 April - June (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1960 July - September (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1960 October - December (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1961 January - March (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1961 April - June (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1961 July - September (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1961 October - December (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1962 January - March (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1962 April - June (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1962 July - September (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1962 October - December (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1963 January - March (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1963 April - June (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1963 July - September (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1963 October - December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1964 January - March (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1964 April - June (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1964 July - September (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1964 October - December (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1965 January - March (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1965 April - June (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1965 July - September (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1965 October - December (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1966 January - March (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1966 April - June (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1966 July - September (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1966 October - December (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1967 January - March (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1967 April - June (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1967 July - September (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1967 October - December (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1968 January - March (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1968 April - June (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1968 July - September (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1968 October - December (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1969 January - March (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1969 April - June (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1969 July - September (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1969 October - December (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1970 January - March (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1970 April - June (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1970 July - September (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1970 October - December (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1971 January - March (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1971 April - June (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1971 July - September (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1971 October - December (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1972 January - March (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1972 April - June (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1972 July - September (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1972 October - December (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1973 January - March (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1973 April - June (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1973 July - September (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1973 October - December (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1974 January - March (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1974 April - June (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1974 July - September (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1974 October - December (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1975 January - March (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1975 April - June (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1975 July - September (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1975 October - December (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1976 January - March (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1976 April - June (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1976 July - September (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1976 October - December (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1977 January - March (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1977 April - June (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1977 July - September (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1977 October - December (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1978 January - March (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1978 April - June (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1978 July - September (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1978 October - December (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1979 January - March (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1979 April - June (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1979 July - September (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1979 October - December (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1980 January - March (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1980 April - June (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1980 July - September (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1980 October - December (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1981 January - March (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1981 April - June (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1981 July -September (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1981 October - December (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1982 January - March (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1982 April - June (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1982 July - September (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1982 October - December (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1983 January - March (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1983 April - June (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1983 July - September (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1983 October - December (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1984 January - March (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1984 April - June (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1984 July - September (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1984 October - December (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1985 January - March (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1985 April - June (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1985 July - September (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1985 October - December (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1986 January - March (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1986 April - June (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1986 July - September (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1986 October - December (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1987 January - March (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1987 April - June (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1987 July - September (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1987 October - December (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1988 January - March (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1988 April - June (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1988 July - September (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1988 October - December (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1989 January - March (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1989 April -June (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1989 July - September (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1989 October - December (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 1990 January - March (Box 9A, Folder 1)
  - 1990 April - June (Box 9A, Folder 2)
  - 1990 July - September (Box 9A, Folder 3)
  - 1990 October - December (Box 9A, Folder 4)
  - 1991 January - March (Box 9A, Folder 5)
  - 1991 April - June (Box 9A, Folder 6)
  - 1991 July - September (Box 9A, Folder 7)
  - 1991 October - December (Box 9A, Folder 8)
  - 1992 January - March (Box 9A, Folder 9)
  - 1992 April - June (Box 9A, Folder 10)
  - 1992 July - September (Box 9A, Folder 11)
  - 1992 October - December (Box 9A, Folder 12)
  - 1993 January - June (Box 9A, Folder 13)
  - 1993 July - December (Box 9A, Folder 14)
  - 1994 January - June (Box 9A, Folder 15)
  - 1994 July - December (Box 9A, Folder 16)
  - 1995 January - June (Box 9B, Folder 1)
  - 1995 July - December (Box 9B, Folder 2)
  - 1996 January - June (Box 9B, Folder 3)
  - 1996 July - December (Box 9B, Folder 4)
  - 1997 January - February (Box 9B, Folder 5)
  - 1997 March - April (Box 9B, Folder 6)
  - 1997 May - June (Box 9B, Folder 7)
  - 1997 July - 1998 (Box 9B, Folder 8)
  - Anvil History of California (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ALPBACH Summer Institute (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Australia Tour, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Burlingame, Michael Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - California Illustrated Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Giant Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Fund Lectures - London, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Craven Conference, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Dred Scott, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Dred Scott, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Dred Scott, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Fleming Lectures Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Goldentree Bibliography (Manifest Destiny...) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - History in the Schools, Meetings and Transcript (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Institute of American History, 1972-1977 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Institute of American History, 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Ireland Lecture Tour, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lamar Lectures (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Library of America Lincoln, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Library of America Lincoln, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Library of America Lincoln, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Library of America Lincoln, Comments on Specific Items (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Lilly Summer Seminar, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lincoln Herald (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lincoln in Text and Context (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lincoln-Selected Works, New American Library, Stanford University Press (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln Sites Project, 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Educational Testing Service (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Florentine Films, Ken Burns' The Civil War (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association, Membership Committee (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The Minor Affair (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The Munich Symposium, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - The National Video Project on Constitution (Failed), 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Neal, Ellen; Correspondence on Dissertation (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Pacific Coast Branch, AHA Program Committee, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Pacific Coast Branch, AHA Presidency, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Potter, David; Correspondence General, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Potter, David; Correspondence Concerning His Impending Crisis (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Potter, David; Copies of His Letters Concerning Impending Crisis (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Prelude to Greatness Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Project '87 Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Project '87 Seminar, Summer, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Reconstruction of American History--Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Reviews in American History Editorial Board (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Sectional Crisis and Southern Constitutionalism, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Wiley Texts, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Wiley Texts, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Wiley Texts, 1968-70 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Wiley Texts, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Wiley Texts, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - William and Mary, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- CLASS MATERIALS, SERIES 2
  - Basic Seminar Exercises (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Writing History (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Presidency--Exams (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Presidency--Trivia Quizzes (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Presidency--Class Lists (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Presidency--Syllabi (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Presidency--Class Notes (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Colloquium--Class Notes (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Race and Slavery--Class Notes (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Bellum US--Lectures (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Civil War--Syllabi, Exams (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Civil War and Reconstruction--Lectures I (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Civil War and Reconstruction--Lectures II (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - History of California--Syllabi (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - History of California--Exams (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - History of California--Lectures (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Nineteenth Century America--Syllabi (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Nineteenth Century America--Examinations (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Nineteenth Century America--Lectures (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - West to 1860 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 158: The Great West (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Alpbach Lectures on Nineteenth Century America (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Cliveden Lecture Course--Anglo-American Relations (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Cliveden Seminar--English Revolutions (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Class Evaluations (Box 14, Folder 7)
- WRITINGS, DRED SCOTT CASE, SERIES 3
  - Publisher's Draft, Introduction-Chapter 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part I, Chapters 3-4 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part I, Chapters 5-6 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part I, Chapters 7-8 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part II, Chapters 9-12 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part II, Chapters 13-15 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part II, Chapters 16-17 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part III, Chapters 18-20 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Publisher's Draft, Part III, Chapters 21-23 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Publisher's Draft, Footnotes: Introduction-Chapter 5 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Comments on the Dred Scott Case manuscript by two Oxford readers: William Wiecek and Robert Johannsen, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Publisher's Draft, Footnotes: Chapters 6-15 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Publisher's Draft, Footnotes: Chapters 16-23 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - First Draft, Introduction-Slavery (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - First Draft, Chapter II (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - First Draft, Expansion I (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - First Draft, Expansion II (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - First Draft, Expansion III (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - First Draft, Chapter 8, Judicial (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - First Draft, Chapter 9, Travels (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - First Draft, Chapter 10, Missouri (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - First Draft, Chapter 11, Sanford (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - First Draft, Chapter 12, Supreme Court (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - First Draft, Chapter 13, Voices (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - First Draft, Chapter 14, What (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - First Draft, Chapter 15, Opinion (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - First Draft, Chapter 16, Opinion Territories (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - First Draft, Chapter 17, Concurrence (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - First Draft, Chapter 18, The Judges (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - First Draft, Chapter 19, Not Peace (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - First Draft, Chapter 20, Not Peace II (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - First Draft, Chapter 21, Not Peace III (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - First Draft, Chapter 22, Reasons Why (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - First Draft, Chapter 23 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- WRITINGS, LINCOLN, SERIES 4
  - Nomination of Lincoln (1858), 1950 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln to Mayor of Chicago, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln-Douglas Debates, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - House-Divided Speech, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln, Douglas, and the Freeport Question, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Lincoln and Judicial Supremacy, Galena Speech (1856), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Lincoln and Reconstruction (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Lincoln in Churchill History--BPC, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln and the Weight of Responsibility, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Lincoln Garraty Encyclopedia, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Mazenod Lincoln (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Lincoln, Chicago-Charleston Comparison, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln and the Paradoxes of Freedom, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Minor Affair, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Death of Lincoln, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Lincoln in Fiction (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - The Fictional Lincoln, Stanford Magazine, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - 100 Days--Launching a Wartime Presidency, Becker Lecture I (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - 100 Days--Launching a Wartime Presidency, Becker Lecture II (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Dred Scott Fragment, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Lincoln--The New Book of Knowledge (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Lincoln Lectures--misc. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Lincoln and the Mississippi (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln and Reconstruction (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln and the Meaning of Appomattox (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cox Paper Critique (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Comment on Boritt, Oates (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - William E. Barton Term Paper, circa 1948 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- WRITINGS, MINOR AFFAIR, SERIES 5
  - Published Pamphlet (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic Staff (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Ellery Sedgwick (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Wilma Francis Minor (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Atlantic Articles (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Paul Angle--Letters Sent (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Paul Angle--Letters Received (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Angle Reprints (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - William E. Barton (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers on First Installment, Nov-Dec 1928; (photocopies) (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers on Second Installment, 1929; (photocopies) (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - End of the Affair Newspaper Clippings, 1929; (photocopies) (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1928; (photocopies) (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Critiques--Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, clippings, 1931-1981 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- WRITINGS, GENERAL, SERIES 6
  - Ancestors Piece, American Heritage (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Christian Advocate (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Cornell College Commencement Address (Also Stanford Phi Beta Kappa earlier), 1970 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Constitutional History, 1848-1861, Encyclopedia of the Constitution (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Dred Scott Essay, Encyclopedia of the Constitution (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Encyclopedia Articles (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Federal Government and Slavery--Claremont (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Fleming Lectures as Presented (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "Husk" Pieces (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Judd-Wentworth Feud (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Legacy from the Gilded Age, Stanford Centennial (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Magazines and the Boldonis (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - New Political History (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Pacific States (Grolier) (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Post Office in Illinois Politics (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Potter--Encyclopedia Article (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Potter--Memorial Resolution (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Race and Slavery--"This Constitution" (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Retirement Remarks in History Newsletter (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Roger B. Taney and the Sectional Crisis (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Two Casualties of War in War Comes Again (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "Southern Review"--Missouri Controversy (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Wentworth--Chicago Tribune (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The World & I--Abolish Vice Presidency (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Review of Justice Accused (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Freehling Review (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Anderson, Stozier Review (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Review of Safire's Freedom (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Stampp Review (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Swisher Review (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Reviews--Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Clippings of Reviews (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Editorial Critiques (Box 21, Folder 14)
- REVIEWS OF HIS WORK, SERIES 7
  - Chicago Giant--Reviews (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Politics and the Crisis of 1860 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Prelude to Greatness (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Reconstruction of American History (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - A Basic History of California (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Abraham Lincoln: A Documentary Portrait (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - The Changing Image of Lincoln... (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Reviews of California Illustrated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Era of Expansion (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - The Leadership of Abraham Lincoln (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Dred Scott Reviews (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Dred Scott Case--Extra Copies and Articles (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Minor Affair (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - The Public and the Private Lincoln (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The South and Three Sectional Crises (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Slavery, Law and Politics... (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Abraham Lincoln and the American Political Tradition (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln in Text and Context--Reviews (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Slavery and its Consequences (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Reviews--History of Liberty (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Reviews of Constitutions and Constitutionalism... (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Library of America: Lincoln--Reviews (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Reviews, Potter's The South and the Concurrent Majority (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Reviews, Potter's History and American Society (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Reviews, Potter's The Impending Crisis (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Reviews, Potter's Freedom and its Limitations... (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Reviews of "The Civil War" (film) (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Additional Material
  - The Chicago Democrat and the sectional crisis, 1854-1961. Fehrenbacher's Master's Thesis, University of Chicago., 1948 (Box 1)
Related/Analytical Title
The Dred Scott case: its significance in American law and politics.
Related/Analytical Title
The Minor affair: an adventure in forgery and detection.
PARTIAL INDEX TO CORRESPONDENTS
The following is a partial listing of correspondents in Series 1 and the year(s) where their letters may be found.